<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Baki Cakici</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Baki Cakici</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spaceships and Poetry: Enlivening the Lab as a Site of Feminist Critical Pedagogy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/spaceships2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/spaceships2024/</guid>
      <description>We analyse the critical potential of STS lab work in technical environments and provide recommendations from our evolving space of feminist praxis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Seamlessness: A Rights Claims Perspective on Digital Identification Technologies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/seamlessness2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/seamlessness2024/</guid>
      <description>We analyse seamlessness and political participation as digital identification becomes the invisible background of state-citizen interactions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Numbers Run Out: Civil Registration and the Performativity of Methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/numbers2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/numbers2024/</guid>
      <description>Personal identification numbers used in the Nordic countries contain a fundamental tension that is impossible to resolve via technical fixes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CASE: A Framework for Computer Supported Outbreak Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/case2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/case2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer supported outbreak detection, a statistical method is applied to a collection of cases to detect any excess cases for a particular disease. Whether a detected aberration is a true outbreak is decided by a human expert. We present a technical framework designed and implemented at the Swedish Institute for Infectious Disease Control for computer supported outbreak detection, where a database of case reports for a large number of infectious diseases can be processed using one or more statistical methods selected by the user.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
