<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Baki Cakici</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Baki Cakici</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Parents as Citizens and Consumers: Local Variations in Informational Material about School Allocation and Choice in Sweden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/configuring2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/configuring2025/</guid>
      <description>Children and their families in Sweden might encounter different understandings of education depending on which municipality they live in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spaceships and Poetry: Enlivening the Lab as a Site of Feminist Critical Pedagogy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/spaceships2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/spaceships2024/</guid>
      <description>We analyse the critical potential of STS lab work in technical environments and provide recommendations from our evolving space of feminist praxis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Seamlessness: A Rights Claims Perspective on Digital Identification Technologies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/seamlessness2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/seamlessness2024/</guid>
      <description>We analyse seamlessness and political participation as digital identification becomes the invisible background of state-citizen interactions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Numbers Run Out: Civil Registration and the Performativity of Methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/numbers2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/numbers2024/</guid>
      <description>Personal identification numbers used in the Nordic countries contain a fundamental tension that is impossible to resolve via technical fixes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risken är att att 500 miljoner kronor kastas bort på en ny folkräkning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/risken2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/risken2023/</guid>
      <description>Mot bakgrund av kunskapsläget är vi förvånade över att regeringen och Sverigedemokraterna avser att driva igenom att Sverige ska genomföra en folkräkning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Bodies and Bodies of Text: Thinking Vulnerability Through Monsters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/monsters2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/monsters2022/</guid>
      <description>We suggest approaching writing as a vulnerable practice marked by an unstable boundary between bodies: bodies of text and bodies of writers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Practices: Making Up a European People</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/datapractices2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/datapractices2021/</guid>
      <description>The book develops a conception of data practices to analyze findings from collaborative ethnographic multisite fieldwork as part of a five-year project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Subjects: Calibrating and Sieving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/datasubjects2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/datasubjects2021/</guid>
      <description>Who are the subjects of data practices? How do data practices configure the capacities of subjects to become part of a population?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistician Subjects: Differentiating and Defending</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/statsubjects2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/statsubjects2021/</guid>
      <description>We consider how the statistician subject is being shaped, and the profession of national statistician repositioned, through professionalising practices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upon Not Opening The Black Box</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/blackbox2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/blackbox2020/</guid>
      <description>We offer a discussion on the value of data, its use and non-use, as well as how to live with this ambivalence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methods as Forces of Subjectivation: Experiments in the Remaking of Official Statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/subjectivation2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/subjectivation2020/</guid>
      <description>We develop the concept of methods as forces of subjectivation in relation to experiments we have encountered in a study of official population statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peopling Europe through Data Practices: Introduction to the Special Issue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/peopling2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/peopling2020/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to say, I am European? Where does Europe begin and end? Who can legitimately claim to be a part of a European people?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing a Transversal Method: Developing an Ethics of Care in a Collaborative Research Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/transversal2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/transversal2019/</guid>
      <description>We depart from some conceptual presuppositions of methodological cosmopolitanism to define a transversal method.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Mystery: Putting Algorithmic Accountability in Context</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/mystery2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/mystery2019/</guid>
      <description>We cannot stop at denouncing the lack of accountability for algorithms but must engage the broader systems and that algorithmic systems exist within.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Data and Trust in Official Statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/citizendata2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/citizendata2018/</guid>
      <description>In a time of alternative facts, what constitutes legitimate knowledge and expertise are major political sites of contention and struggle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Scientists: A New Faction of the Transnational Field of Statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/datascientists2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/datascientists2018/</guid>
      <description>We discuss how data science as a  field and a profession came into being in relation to but also as a critique of existing ones such as statistics and statisticians.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regarding the Constants of Nature and of Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/constants2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/constants2018/</guid>
      <description>Babbage’s constants and engines exemplified a rationality which emphasised counting and measurement as essential means for legitimate knowledge production.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggering Action: Participatory Surveillance and Event Detection in Public Emergency Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/action2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/action2017/</guid>
      <description>Our chapter is informed by work that theorizes the relationship between knowledge of populations and modes of governance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Data and Official Statistics: Background Document to a Collaborative Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/citizendata2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/citizendata2017/</guid>
      <description>This working paper was written in preparation for a collaborative workshop organised for statisticians, social scientists, and app designers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transcending Methodological Nationalism Through a Transversal Method? On the Stakes and Challenges of Collaboration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/transcending2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/transcending2016/</guid>
      <description>This paper reflects on the challenges of doing collaborative ethnography in a research project (ARITHMUS) that studies the enactment of populations through statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing Behaviour to Save Energy: ICT-Based Surveillance for a Low-Carbon Economy in the Seventh Framework Programme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/changing2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/changing2014/</guid>
      <description>EU FP7 texts discuss only the potential positive effects of technological surveillance, but neither acknowledge nor require the handling of its negative effects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICT4S 2029: What Will Be the Systems Supporting Sustainability in 15 Years?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/systems2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/systems2014/</guid>
      <description>What is your vision for systems that will be supporting sustainability in 15 years?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting the Visible: The Discursive Construction of Health Threats in a Syndromic Surveillance System Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/detecting2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/detecting2014/</guid>
      <description>Information and communication technologies are not value-neutral tools that reflect reality; they privilege some forms of action, and they limit others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Informed Gaze: On the Implications of ICT-Based Surveillance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/phd2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/phd2013/</guid>
      <description>Information and communication technologies are not value-neutral.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability Through Surveillance: ICT Discourses in Design Documents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/survsoc2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/survsoc2013/</guid>
      <description>Surveillance translates the traces, and the translations exert new pressures on existing power relations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Workflow for Software Development Within Computational Epidemiology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/workflow2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/workflow2011/</guid>
      <description>A critical investigation into computational models developed for studying the spread of communicable disease is presented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disease Surveillance Systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/phlic2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/phlic2011/</guid>
      <description>This thesis presents a method for understanding disease surveillance systems structurally and examines four existing systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CASE: A Framework for Computer Supported Outbreak Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/case2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/case2010/</guid>
      <description>We present a technical framework designed and implemented at the Swedish Institute for Infectious Disease Control for computer supported outbreak detection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic consequences to society of pandemic H1N1 influenza 2009 — preliminary results for Sweden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/eurosurv2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/eurosurv2009/</guid>
      <description>Experiments using a microsimulation platform show that vaccination against pandemic H1N1 influenza is highly cost-effective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MicroSim: Modeling the Swedish Population</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/microsim2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/microsim2009/</guid>
      <description>This article presents a spatially explicit microsimulation model that uses official anonymized register data collected from all individuals living in Sweden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pickman’s Machine: A Reasoning Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/msc2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/msc2008/</guid>
      <description>A two-layered architecture for reasoning that uses narratives to guide its behavior is presented.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
